One of the most popular application areas for voice system today is conversational AI.
如今语音系统最流行的应用领域是对话式 AI
We've just seen a demonstration of the Amazon Alexa and a variety of
我们已经了解过亚马逊 Alexa 的演示和
Amazon skills that can run on Amazon echo devices using voice only interface.
使用语音界面的亚马逊 Echo 设备上亚马逊的技能
We're fortunate to have a subject matter expert on this technology with us now.
现在我们很幸运邀请了这项技术的论题专家
I'd like to introduce Jeff Blankenburg-- Alexa Evangelist at Amazon.
我非常高兴向大家介绍亚马逊 Alexa Evangelist 的 Jeff Blankenburg
He's here to educate us on the Amazon Echo and Alexa.
在这里他会向我们讲授亚马逊的 Echo 和 Alexa
Jeff, we're so glad you're here.
Jeff 很高兴你的到来
Thanks. Dana, thanks for inviting me to be a part of this.
谢谢 Dana 谢谢你邀请我来到这部分内容
I'm really excited about what Udacity is doing to help developers learn about Alexa.
我非常高兴优达学城正在进行的项目 帮助开发人员了解 Alexa
We are too. In this lesson,
我们也是 在这节课中
we're going to learn how to build our own Alexa skill.
我们要学习如何构建自己的 Alexa 技能
Jeff, for a little background.
Jeff 提供一些背景知识
Could you tell us how Conversational AI at
你可以告诉我们亚马逊的对话式 AI
Amazon got started and have the Echo and Alexa came to be?
如何启动的？如何发展成为 Echo 和 Alexa 呢？
Sure. The original inspiration for the Amazon Echo was the Star Trek computer.
当然 亚马逊 Echo 的最初灵感是星际迷航的计算机
We wanted to create a computer in the cloud that
我们想要创建云端计算机
controlled everything entirely by your voice.
可以根据你的声音完全控制一切
You could ask it questions,
你可以提问
turn lights on and off,
开灯关灯
and order stuff for yourself,
以及一些命令
and it's easy to talk in a natural way.
这样说起来很容易
We're a ways off from a Star Trek vision,
我们远离星际迷航的视野
but that was our inspiration.
不过这是我们的灵感
The cool thing about all of this,
整件事有趣的地方在于
is that we're really at a tipping point for so many elements of the technology.
我们实际上处于这项技术许多元素的临界点
We're still a long way from being able to do things the way humans do things.
不过能够让这些东西像人类一样 还需要很长时间
But we're still solving unbelievably complex problems everyday.
不过我们还是解决了难以置信的日常复杂问题
And as we've seen over the past two years,
正如我们过去两年所见
conversational computing is popular.
对话式计算非常流行
I think a primary reason for this is because it's so accessible.
我认为主要原因在于这是可获取的
Echo devices are designed for families to use together.
Echo 设备是针对家庭共同使用而设计的
What we hear from parents and other customers is that
我们从父母和其他顾客那里得知
Alexa provides great fun for the whole family.
Alexa 为整个家庭带来巨大乐趣
It's clear. The conversational aspect makes all the difference.
这是显而易见的 对话方面具有重大影响
In the past we've seen voice systems on phones that step you
过去我们了解到手机上的语音系统
through the menu but under some circumstances that can be frustrating.
让你跳过菜单 不过一些情况下令人失望
It sounds like Alexa is a big step up from that kind of voice interface.
Alexa 听起来是这些语音界面的较大进步
Exactly. The phone systems you're talking about took
没错 你提到的手机系统采用了
an approach the industry calls graph based interaction.
行业所谓的基于图像互动方法
I think this was a choice of necessity because most phone system technologies were built
我认为这是必备的选择 因为如今我们拥有丰富的对话式用户界面
before we had some of the rich Conversational UI that we have today.
此前大部分手机系统的技术就已经创建了
Graph based interaction mainly focuses on asking pointed questions
基于图像的互动 主要侧重于提问既定顺序的尖锐问题
in a prescribed order and only accepting specific terms as responses.
只能接受特定项目作为响应
You've seen this plenty of times before when
你已经见过这个很多次
you can't move forward in the system until you provide
在此之前你无法在系统中移动
your user ID or you can't specify
直到你提供了用户 ID
your destination until you provided the location you'll be starting from.
或者是你指明出发地点后才能指定目的地
Here's the example: Alexa,
下面是个例子 Alexa
open graph travel agent.
打开地图旅行代理 (graph travel agent)
Where are you flying from?
你要飞往哪里？
I want to fly from Columbus to San Francisco on October 9th.
我想在 10 月 9 号从哥伦布飞往旧金山
You're flying from Columbus.
你要从哥伦布起飞
Got it. Where do you want to go?
明白 你想要去哪里？
San Francisco on Delta flight 722.
乘坐达美航班 722 前往旧金山
Okay. You're trying to find a flight from Columbus to San Francisco.
好 你试图找到从哥伦布飞往旧金山的航班
Which airline do you want to use?
你想使用哪个航空公司呢？
You can see how that can get a little frustrating.
你会发现这有点令人失望
The alternative frame based allows the user to drive the interaction.
其他框架能够让用户引导互动
You can say the words that make sense to you.
你可以说出对你有意义的词语
You can make requests in the order you prefer when it makes sense and you can jump
它有意义时 你可以提出自己喜欢顺序的请求
to the part of the menu you want to be in without having to memorize a list of options.
不需要记忆一系列选项就可以跳到想要的部分
Alexa. Open frame travel agent.
Alexa 打开地图旅行代理 (graph travel agent)
Where are you flying from?
你要飞往哪里？
I want to fly from Columbus to San Francisco on October 9th.
我想在 10 月 9 号从哥伦布飞往旧金山
Okay. You're trying to find a flight from Columbus to San Francisco on October 9th.
好 你试图找到 10 月 9 号从哥伦布飞往旧金山的航班
Which airline do you want to use?
你想使用哪个航空公司呢？
That's so exciting.
这非常振奋人心
It's exciting because it means there's a lot of flexibility in what we can build,
令人高兴的是 这意味着我们设计自己的 Alexa 技能时
when we design our own Alexa skills.
构建的内容具有很强的灵活性
But how do we know what we want to have Alexa listen for?
不过我们怎样知道想让 Alexa 倾听哪些内容呢？
And how does that translate to what we want in response?
它怎样翻译成我们想要的响应呢？
In the example, you just showed Alexa was very accommodating.
在这个例子中 你只展示了 Alexa 非常方便
One of the cool things about building a Voice User Interface or VUI,
构建语音用户界面 (VUI) 比较有意思的一件事是
is how you define interactions with your users.
你如何定义与用户之间的互动
You get to define a series of actions that the user can perform which we call intense.
你需要定义用户执行的一系列动作 也是我们所谓的意图
If our voice skill was a DVD player,
如果你的语音技巧是 DVD 播放机
our intense might be play,
我们的 intense 可能是播放
pause, stop, and eject.
暂停 停止和弹出
Our DVD player doesn't have a pizza button
我们的 DVD 播放器没有比萨按键
because DVD players don't traditionally make pizzas.
因为 DVD 播放器不能制作比萨
We then create a set of sample statements which we call utterances that
然后我们创建一套样本语句 叫做话语 (utterance)
help Alexa understand which intent to use when a user says something.
可以帮助 Alexa 理解用户说话时使用什么意图
Going back to the DVD player example,
回到 DVD 播放器例子中
someone might say "start the movie" and they would expect the play intent to happen.
有人说 “启动电影” 他们想实现播放目的
But they might also say play or go or begin
但是如果他们也说播放或者开始
or it's show time and they would expect to have the same reaction.
或者表演时间到 他们也说希望实现相同动作
The intention is to play the movie.
目的是播放电影
These example utterances help elect to understand
这些例子 “话语” 帮助 选择理解
which intent should be called when the user says something to a skill.
用户对某个技能说话时所谓的意图
I see. So if we think about a sort of script we want our user to have with Alexa,
我明白了 那么如果我们考虑让用户使用一些字幕与 Alexa 交流
we can come up with a number of different ways they might converse.
我们想到它们交谈的各种不同方式
I guess more user testing could help us expand our list of better answers as well.
我猜更多用户测试也可以帮我们拓展更优答案的列表
How do we model what the user will say?
我们怎样模拟用户说话的内容呢？
This is one of my favorite questions to answer.
这是我最喜欢回答的一个问题
I spend a great deal of my time working with software developers that are building
我花费大量时间与软件开发人员工作
their first or second skill for
为 Alexa 构建第一个和第二个技能
Alexa and that is one of the most common questions I encounter.
这是我遇到最常见的一个问题
What's the best tool for modeling my conversation with my users?
模拟我与用户的对话最好的工具是什么呢？
The surprising or maybe not so surprising answer is to grab a couple of your colleagues,
答案可能令人吃惊 也很平常 就是抓住你的同事
friends, and complete strangers and ask them to naturally request what outcome they need.
朋友或者陌生人 询问他们他们对请求需要得到的结果
Take some notes because you will quickly discover that every person is
记录一些笔记 因为你很快发现所有人
going to approach the process of this a slightly different way,
都以略有不同的方式处理这个过程
and your skills should be able to accommodate all of them.
你的技巧能够容纳所有内容
An example of this, when you ask Alexa for the weather.
例如 当你向 Alexa 提问天气时
You could say what does the temperature outside?
你会说外面气温是多少？
Or how hot is it?
或者是多么热呢？
But you can also just say,
不过你可能也只说
Alexa, what's it like?
Alexa 天气怎么样
In Mountain View, it's 58 degrees with cloudy skies.
在山景城 阴天时气温是 58 度
Today, you can look for lots of clouds with a high of 69 degrees and a low of 50 degrees.
今天你会发现多云天气 最高气温 69 度 最低气温 50 度
There are hundreds of ways to indicate that you want
可能有几百种方式表明
to know the weather without saying it explicitly.
你含蓄地说出想知道天气情况
That sounds like fun.
这听起来很有趣
Students could even ask others in the classroom and sort of crowdsource,
课堂上学生甚至可能会问其他人 像是众筹一样
a list of possible utterances.
列出潜在的话语
But before we start building a skill,
不过在我们开始构建技能前
are there some other guidelines we need to keep in mind for a good user experience?
为了更好的用户体验 我们是不是要记住其他准则呢？
I think you're touching on the best practices in VUI
我认为你提到了 VUI 设计的最佳实践中
design that we need to remain aware of as we build skills.
我们在创建技能时要谨记的内容
There are a number of ideas to consider when designing a voice only interface.
设计语音界面时 有一些需要考虑的想法
There are different from design of say,
这不同于文本设计
text or graphical interfaces.
或图像界面
This sounds important.
这听起来很重要
Let's dig a little deeper.
我们来更深入研究一下